operamail.com 2013-05-01

# Overview - Our Privacy Policy

FastMail.FM regards the privacy of its users seriously. This privacy policy applies to all of the FastMail.FM services. The FastMail.FM privacy policy is guided by the National Privacy Principles under the Privacy Act 1988. If you have any questions about our privacy policy please email privacy@fastmail.fm. 

In accordance with the guidelines we disclose that we provide electronic messaging services. 

We disclose our practices regarding the following information: 

  1. The information we collect, and its purpose

  2. How we use and disclose your information

  3. How we store your information

  4. Viewing, correcting and updating personally identifiable information 

  5. Our policy on removing your information

  6. Our opt-out policy

  7. Information collected by other parties

  8. Co-Branding

### The information we collect and its purpose

  * Information about you - When you sign up to use a FastMail.FM service we ask for personal information such as your name and email address. We also ask you to select a username and password. If you register for a service that requires payment we may request credit card and address details which we will store on our servers. 

  * Cookies - We use cookies to enhance the functionality of our services. Cookies are files sent to your web browser. You can set your browser to reject cookies but some of our features may not work if you do not accept our cookies. 

  * Server logs - Our servers record information sent by your browsers and email software when you use our services. These logs include information such as the IP address, software type and version, timestamps and cookies that identify your browser. 

  * Direct communications - When you communicate with FastMail.FM using email, telephone or post we may keep copies of the communication. 

FastMail.FM only uses this information for the purpose of providing our services unless otherwise required or allowed by law. 

### How we use and disclose your information

We will only disclose or use personally identifiable information where: 

  * Law enforcement agencies have either provided us with the required legal documentation or court order, or the disclosure or use is reasonably necessary for the enforcement of criminal law; or 

  * To protect and defend the rights or property of the Service Provider; or 

  * To enforce the terms of service; or 

  * To act to protect the interests of its members or others; or 

  * To facilitate a change of control of the Service Provider or the acquisition of the Service Provider's business by a third party, and to enable that third party to continue to provide the FastMail.FM services to you. 

  * You have given us your consent.

**Non-paying users only:**

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. 

Where possible, we use advertisers that conform to the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI"), a cooperative of online marketing and analytics companies committed to building consumer awareness and establishing responsible business and data management practices and standards. The NAI includes an opt-out facility available [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

### How we store your information

We will take all reasonable steps to keep secure any information we hold about you and to keep this information accurate and up to date. Your information is stored on secure servers that are protected in controlled facilities. In addition, our employees and any contractors who provide services related to our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by us. However, we will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access to your personal information. 

###  Accessing, correcting and updating personal information 

You have certain rights to access your personal information held by FastMail.FM. If you wish to access any personal information that we hold about you, please send your request to us by email to privacy@fastmail.fm. You can also update your personal information using the Options/Preferences screen or the Options/Subscription Details screen 

### Our policy on removing your information

When you delete messages or files, or update your personal information, the previous information is removed from our live system. However, the information may still exist in backups and log files, and it may not be practicable to completely remove all copies of the information. 

By using FastMail.FM, you agree to FastMail.FM sending you information about the Service from time to time. We will not send you unsolicited email messages or Spam from third parties. 

### Information collected by other parties

We may permit other parties to collect non-personal information about the usage patterns of our services. We do this only to improve the service. 

We may share email you report as spam with third parties for the purpose of assisting in industry initiatives to control undesirable email. You may opt-out of this via an option in the web interface. 

There are a number of Co-Branded sites which resell FastMail.FM services under their own branding. Such Co-Branded sites operate under their own terms and conditions and privacy policy. Before disclosing your personal information to any Co-Branded sites, you should read the relevant policy or terms of use. In some cases, the specific terms on the Co-Branded site will override FastMail.FM's own policies. 

If we change our information usage practices that affect your personal information we will notify you of the relevant changes by posting a notice on our web site. If the changes are significant we may also send an email message to your FastMail.FM account and backup email address, if defined. 

If you have any questions about our privacy policy please [ email privacy@fastmail.fm.](mailto:privacy@fastmail.fm)
